The Crisis Magazine MS251
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
The Crisis Magazine
circa 1916 -- 2009
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
National Association for the Advancement of Colored People
MS251
4.8 Linear Feet
This collection contains issues of The Crisis, the official publication of the NAACP, and other materials created by the NAACP, as well as other publications and ephemera concerning the civil rights of African Americans and related issues.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of James H. Kelly, 2018, accession number MS-2019-031.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged in two series: The Crisis; and Ephemera and related materials.
Biographical / Historical
The Crisis is the official publication of the NAACP. It was founded in 1910 by W.E.B. Du Bois, one year after the founding of the NAACP. The magazine's original purpose was to record the difficulties Black Americans faced finding housing, employment, and educational opportunities, and encountering police brutality and other issues arising from systemic racism. By the end of its first decade, The Crisis had achieved a monthly circulation of 100,000 copies.
The Crisis records the views and campaigns of the NAACP. The magazine has historically included editorials criticizing Woodrow Wilson's policy of mandated segregation in federal offices, the failure of the Dyer Anti-lynching bill to pass in the Senate in the 1920's, and exhibitions of the D.W. Griffith film "The Birth of a Nation," which idealizes the Klu Klux Klan. Additionally, advertisements in the magazine promote opportunities for education, jobs, and real estate. Often, the advertisements reflect the values of the editor at the time; for example, under Du Bois' editorship, advertisements about education were the most prevalent.
The magazine also played a crucial role in supporting writers of the Harlem Renaissance after the appointment of Jessie Redmon Fauset as literary editor. Fauset guided several prominent Black authors in the early stages of their careers, including Arna Bontemps, Langston Hughes, and Countee Cullen.
The Crisis struggled to maintain its circulation after Fauset left the magazine in 1926. Additionally, in 1934, Du Bois left his position as editor after disputes with board members in the NAACP over his opinions on Black separatism. Though the magazine is best known for its years of editorship under Du Bois, The Crisis was praised for its coverage of the civil rights movements during the 1960's, and as of 2018, continues to publish articles which educate readers on challenges facing communities of color.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains issues of The Crisis, the official publication of the NAACP, from 1929 through 2002. This collection also contains publications, a poster, and other documents created by the NAACP, and other publications and ephemera concerning the civil rights of African Americans and related issues.
African Americans -- Civil rights; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People
- The Crisis, 1929 -- 2002; MS251.001; 4.2 Linear Feet 3.5 record cartons
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged in chronological order.
  Conditions Governing Access
  This series is open for research.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains issues of The Crisis, the official publication of the NAACP, from 1929 through 2002.
  - The Crisis, 1929 December; MS251.001.001.00001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Open for research.
    Volume, issue
    36,12
  - The Crisis, 1930 February; MS251.001.001.00002 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    37,2
  - The Crisis, 1930 March; MS251.001.001.00003 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    37,3
  - The Crisis, 1930 April; MS251.001.001.00004 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    37,4
  - The Crisis, 1930 August; MS251.001.001.00005 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    37,8
  - The Crisis, 1930 October; MS251.001.001.00006 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    37,10
  - The Crisis, 1930 November; MS251.001.001.00007 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Crisis, 1931 November; MS251.001.001.00008 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    40,11
  - The Crisis, 1932 May; MS251.001.001.00009 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    41,5
  - The Crisis, 1932 June; MS251.001.001.00010 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    41,6
  - The Crisis, 1932 July; MS251.001.001.00011 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    39,7
  - The Crisis, 1932 September; MS251.001.001.00012 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    39,9
  - The Crisis, 1932 October; MS251.001.001.00013 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    39,10
  - The Crisis, 1932 December; MS251.001.001.00014 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    39,12
  - The Crisis, 1933 January; MS251.001.001.00015 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    40,1
  - The Crisis, 1933 February; MS251.001.001.00016 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    40,2
  - The Crisis, 1933 March; MS251.001.001.00017 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    40,3
  - The Crisis, 1933 May; MS251.001.001.00018 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    40,5
  - The Crisis, 1933 June; MS251.001.001.00019 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    40,6
  - The Crisis, 1933 July; MS251.001.001.00020 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    40,7
  - The Crisis, 1933 August; MS251.001.001.00021 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    40,8
  - The Crisis, 1933 September; MS251.001.001.00022 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    40,9
  - The Crisis, 1933 November; MS251.001.001.00023 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - The Crisis, 1934 January; MS251.001.001.00024 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    41,1
  - The Crisis, 1934 February; MS251.001.001.00025 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    41,2
  - The Crisis, 1934 March; MS251.001.001.00026 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    41,3
  - The Crisis, 1934 April; MS251.001.001.00027 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    41,4
  - The Crisis, 1934 June; MS251.001.001.00028 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - The Crisis, 1934 October; MS251.001.001.00029 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    41,10
  - The Crisis, 1934 December; MS251.001.001.00030 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    41,12
  - The Crisis, 1935 February; MS251.001.001.00031 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    42,2
  - The Crisis, 1935 June; MS251.001.001.00032 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    42,6
  - The Crisis, 1935 August; MS251.001.001.00033 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    42,8
  - The Crisis, 1935 November; MS251.001.001.00034 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    42,11
  - The Crisis, 1935 December; MS251.001.001.00035 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    42,12
  - The Crisis, 1936 January; MS251.001.001.00036 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    43,1
  - The Crisis, 1936 March; MS251.001.001.00037 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    43,3
  - The Crisis, 1936 April; MS251.001.001.00038 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    43,4
  - The Crisis, 1936 May; MS251.001.001.00039 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    43,5
  - The Crisis, 1936 June; MS251.001.001.00040 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    43,6
  - The Crisis, 1936 July; MS251.001.001.00041 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    43,7
  - The Crisis, 1936 September; MS251.001.001.00042 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    43,9
  - The Crisis, 1936 October; MS251.001.001.00043 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    43,10
  - The Crisis, 1936 November; MS251.001.001.00044 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    43,11
  - The Crisis, 1936 December; MS251.001.001.00045 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    43,12
  - The Crisis, 1937 January; MS251.001.001.00046 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    44,1
  - The Crisis, 1937 February; MS251.001.001.00047 (Box 1, Folder 47)
    44,2
  - The Crisis, 1937 March; MS251.001.001.00048 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    44,3
  - The Crisis, 1937 April; MS251.001.001.00049 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    44,4
  - The Crisis, 1937 May; MS251.001.001.00050 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    44,5
  - The Crisis, 1937 June; MS251.001.001.00051 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    44,6
  - The Crisis, 1937 July; MS251.001.001.00052 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    44,7
  - The Crisis, 1937 August; MS251.001.001.00053 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    44,8
  - The Crisis, 1937 September; MS251.001.001.00054 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    44,9
  - The Crisis, 1937 October; MS251.001.001.00055 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    44,10
  - The Crisis, 1937 November; MS251.001.001.00056 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    44,11
  - The Crisis, 1937 December; MS251.001.001.00057 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    44,12
  - The Crisis, 1938 January; MS251.001.001.00058 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    45,1
  - The Crisis, 1938 February; MS251.001.001.00059 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    45,2
  - The Crisis, 1938 March; MS251.001.001.00060 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    45,3
  - The Crisis, 1938 April; MS251.001.001.00061 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    45,4
  - The Crisis, 1938 May; MS251.001.001.00062 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    45,5
  - The Crisis, 1938 June; MS251.001.001.00063 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    45,6
  - The Crisis, 1938 July; MS251.001.001.00064 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    45,7
  - The Crisis, 1938 August; MS251.001.001.00065 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    45,8
  - The Crisis, 1938 September; MS251.001.001.00066 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    45,9
  - The Crisis, 1938 October; MS251.001.001.00067 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    45,10
  - The Crisis, 1938 November; MS251.001.001.00068 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    45,11
  - The Crisis, 1938 December; MS251.001.001.00069 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    45,12
  - The Crisis, 1939 January; MS251.001.001.00070 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    46,1
  - The Crisis, 1939 February; MS251.001.001.00071 (Box 1, Folder 71)
    46,2
  - The Crisis, 1939 March; MS251.001.001.00072 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    46,3
  - The Crisis, 1939 April; MS251.001.001.00073 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    46,4
  - The Crisis, 1939 May; MS251.001.001.00074 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    46,5
  - The Crisis, 1939 June; MS251.001.001.00075 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    46,6
  - The Crisis, 1939 July; MS251.001.001.00076 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    46,7
  - The Crisis, 1939 August; MS251.001.001.00077 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    46,8
  - The Crisis, 1939 September; MS251.001.001.00078 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    46,9
  - The Crisis, 1939 October; MS251.001.001.00079 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    46,10
  - The Crisis, 1939 November; MS251.001.001.00080 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    46,11
  - The Crisis, 1939 December; MS251.001.001.00081 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    46,12
  - The Crisis, 1940 January; MS251.001.001.00082 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    47,1
  - The Crisis, 1940 February; MS251.001.001.00083 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    47,2
  - The Crisis, 1940 March; MS251.001.001.00084 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    47,3
  - The Crisis, 1940 April; MS251.001.001.00085 (Box 1, Folder 85)
    47,4
  - The Crisis, 1940 May; MS251.001.001.00086 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    47,5
  - The Crisis, 1940 June; MS251.001.001.00087 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    47,6
  - The Crisis, 1940 July; MS251.001.001.00088 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    47,7
  - The Crisis, 1940 August; MS251.001.001.00089 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    47,8
  - The Crisis, 1940 September; MS251.001.001.00090 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    47,9
  - The Crisis, 1940 October; MS251.001.001.00091 (Box 1, Folder 91)
    47,10
  - The Crisis, 1940 November; MS251.001.001.00092 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    47,11
  - The Crisis, 1940 December; MS251.001.001.00093 (Box 1, Folder 93)
    47,12
  - The Crisis, 1940 January; MS251.001.001.00094 (Box 1, Folder 94)
    48,1
  - The Crisis, 1941 February; MS251.001.001.00095 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    48,2
  - The Crisis, 1941 March; MS251.001.001.00096 (Box 1, Folder 96)
    48,3
  - The Crisis, 1941 April; MS251.001.001.00097 (Box 1, Folder 97)
    48,4
  - The Crisis, 1941 May; MS251.001.001.00098 (Box 1, Folder 98)
    48,5
  - The Crisis, 1941 June; MS251.001.001.00099 (Box 1, Folder 99)
    48,6
  - The Crisis, 1941 July; MS251.001.001.00100 (Box 1, Folder 100)
    48,7
  - The Crisis, 1941 August; MS251.001.001.00101 (Box 1, Folder 101)
    48,8
  - The Crisis, 1941 September; MS251.001.001.00102 (Box 1, Folder 102)
    48,9
  - The Crisis, 1941 October; MS251.001.001.00103 (Box 1, Folder 103)
    48,10
  - The Crisis, 1941 November; MS251.001.001.00104 (Box 1, Folder 104)
    48,11
  - The Crisis, 1941 December; MS251.001.001.00105 (Box 1, Folder 105)
    48,12
  - The Crisis, 1941 January; MS251.001.002.00001 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    49,1
  - The Crisis, 1942 February; MS251.001.002.00002 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    49,2
  - The Crisis, 1942 March; MS251.001.002.00003 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    49,3
  - The Crisis, 1942 April; MS251.001.002.00004 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    49,4
  - The Crisis, 1942 May; MS251.001.002.00005 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    49,5
  - The Crisis, 1942 June; MS251.001.002.00006 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    49,6
  - The Crisis, 1942 July; MS251.001.002.00007 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    49,7
  - The Crisis, 1942 August; MS251.001.002.00008 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    49,8
  - The Crisis, 1942 October; MS251.001.002.00009 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    49,10
  - The Crisis, 1942 November; MS251.001.002.00010 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    49,11
  - The Crisis, 1942 December; MS251.001.002.00011 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    49,12
  - The Crisis, 1943 January; MS251.001.002.00012 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    50,1
  - The Crisis, 1943 February; MS251.001.002.00013 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    50,2
  - The Crisis, 1943 March; MS251.001.002.00014 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    50,3
  - The Crisis, 1943 April; MS251.001.002.00015 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    50,4
  - The Crisis, 1943 May; MS251.001.002.00016 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    50,5
  - The Crisis, 1943 June; MS251.001.002.00017 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    50,6
  - The Crisis, 1943 July; MS251.001.002.00018 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    50,7
  - The Crisis, 1943 October; MS251.001.002.00019 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    50,10
  - The Crisis, 1943 November; MS251.001.002.00020 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    50,11
  - The Crisis, 1943 December; MS251.001.002.00021 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    50,12
  - The Crisis, 1944 January; MS251.001.002.00022 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    51,1
  - The Crisis, 1944 February; MS251.001.002.00023 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    51,2
  - The Crisis, 1944 March; MS251.001.002.00024 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    51,3
  - The Crisis, 1944 April; MS251.001.002.00025 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    51,4
  - The Crisis, 1944 May; MS251.001.002.00026 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    51,5
  - The Crisis, 1944 June; MS251.001.002.00027 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    51,6
  - The Crisis, 1944 July; MS251.001.002.00028 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    51,7
  - The Crisis, 1944 August; MS251.001.002.00029 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    51,8
  - The Crisis, 1944 September; MS251.001.002.00030 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    51,9
  - The Crisis, 1944 October; MS251.001.002.00031 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    51,10
  - The Crisis, 1944 November; MS251.001.002.00032 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    51,11
  - The Crisis, 1945 January; MS251.001.002.00033 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    52,1
  - The Crisis, 1945 Febuary; MS250.001.002.00034 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    52,2
  - The Crisis, 1945 March; MS251.001.002.00035 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    52,3
  - The Crisis, 1945 April; MS251.001.002.00036 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    52,4
  - The Crisis, 1945 June; MS251.001.002.00037 (Box 2, Folder 37)
    52,6
  - The Crisis, 1945 July; MS251.001.002.00038 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    52,7
  - The Crisis, 1945 August; MS251.001.002.00039 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    52,8
  - The Crisis, 1945 September; MS251.001.002.00040 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    52,9
  - The Crisis, 1945 October; MS251.001.002.00041 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    52,10
  - The Crisis, 1945 December; MS251.001.002.00042 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    52,12
  - The Crisis, 1946 February; MS251.001.002.00043 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    53,2
  - The Crisis, 1946 March; MS251.001.002.00044 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    53,3
  - The Crisis, 1946 April; MS251.001.002.00045 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    53,4
  - The Crisis, 1946 May; MS251.001.002.00046 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    53,5
  - The Crisis, 1946 June; MS251.001.002.00047 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    53,6
  - The Crisis, 1946 July; MS251.001.002.00048 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    53,7
  - The Crisis, 1946 October; MS251.001.002.00049 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    53,10
  - The Crisis, 1946 November; MS251.001.002.00050 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    53,11
  - The Crisis, 1946 December; MS251.001.002.00051 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    53,12
  - The Crisis, 1947 February; MS251.001.002.00052 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    54,2
  - The Crisis, 1947 March; MS251.001.002.00053 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    54,3
  - The Crisis, 1947 April; MS251.001.002.00054 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    54,4
  - The Crisis, 1947 May; MS251.001.002.00055 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    54,5
  - The Crisis, 1947 June; MS251.001.002.00056 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    54,6
  - The Crisis, 1947 July; MS251.001.002.00057 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    54,7
  - The Crisis, 1947 September; MS251.001.002.00058 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    54,9
  - The Crisis, 1947 October; MS251.001.002.00059 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    54,10
  - The Crisis, 1947 November; MS251.001.002.00060 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    54,11
  - The Crisis, 1947 December; MS251.001.002.00061 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    54,12
  - The Crisis, 1948 January; MS251.001.002.00062 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    55,1
  - The Crisis, 1948 February; MS251.001.002.00063 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    55,2
  - The Crisis, 1948 March; MS251.001.002.00064 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    55,3
  - The Crisis, 1948 April; MS251.001.002.00065 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    55,4
  - The Crisis, 1948 May; MS251.001.002.00066 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    55,5
  - The Crisis, 1948 September; MS251.001.002.00067 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    55,9
  - The Crisis, 1948 October; MS251.001.002.00068 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    55,10
  - The Crisis, 1948 November; MS251.001.002.00069 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    55,11
  - The Crisis, 1948 December; MS251.001.002.00070 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    55,12
  - The Crisis, 1949 January; MS251.001.002.00071 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    56,1
  - The Crisis, 1949 February; MS251.001.002.00072 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    56,2
  - The Crisis, 1949 March; MS251.001.002.00073 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    56,3
  - The Crisis, 1949 April; MS251.001.002.00074 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    56,4
  - The Crisis, 1949 May; MS251.001.002.00075 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    56,5
  - The Crisis, 1949 August-September; MS251.001.002.00076 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    56,8 and 9
  - The Crisis, 1949 October; MS251.001.002.00077 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    56,10
  - The Crisis, 1949 December; MS251.001.002.00078 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    56,11
  - The Crisis, 1950 January; MS251.001.002.00079 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    57,1
  - The Crisis, 1950 February; MS251.001.002.00080 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    57,2
  - The Crisis, 1950 March; MS251.001.002.00081 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    57,3
  - The Crisis, 1950 April; MS251.001.002.00082 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    57,4
  - The Crisis, 1950 May; MS251.001.002.00083 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    57,5
  - The Crisis, 1950 June; MS251.001.002.00084 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    57,6
  - The Crisis, 1950 July; MS251.001.002.00085 (Box 2, Folder 85)
    57,7
  - The Crisis, 1950 October; MS251.001.002.00086 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    57,9
  - The Crisis, 1950 November; MS251.001.002.00087 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    57,10
  - The Crisis, 1950 December; MS251.001.002.00088 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    57,11
  - The Crisis, 1951 January; MS251.001.002.00089 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    58,1
  - The Crisis, 1951 February; MS251.001.002.00090 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    58,2
  - The Crisis, 1951 March; MS251.001.002.00091 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    58,3
  - The Crisis, 1951 April; MS251.001.002.00092 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    58,4
  - The Crisis, 1951 May; MS251.001.002.00093 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    58,5
  - The Crisis, 1951 June-July; MS251.001.002.00094 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    58,6
  - The Crisis, 1951 August-September; MS251.001.002.00095 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    58,7
  - The Crisis, 1951 November; MS251.001.002.00096 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    58,11
  - The Crisis, 1951 December; MS251.001.002.00097 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    58,10
  - The Crisis, 1952 January; MS251.001.002.00098 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    59,1
  - The Crisis, 1952 February; MS251.001.002.00099 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    59,2
  - The Crisis, 1952 March; MS251.001.002.00100 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    59,3
  - The Crisis, 1952 April; MS251.001.002.00101 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    59,4
  - The Crisis, 1952 May; MS251.001.002.00102 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    59,5
  - The Crisis, 1952 October; MS251.001.002.00103 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    59,8
  - The Crisis, 1952 November; MS251.001.002.00104 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    59,9
  - The Crisis, 1952 December; MS251.001.002.00105 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    59,10
  - The Crisis, 1953 January; MS251.001.002.00106 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    60,1
  - The Crisis, 1953 February; MS251.001.002.00107 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    60,2
  - The Crisis, 1953 March; MS251.001.002.00108 (Box 2, Folder 108)
    60,3
  - The Crisis, 1953 April; MS251.001.002.00109 (Box 2, Folder 109)
    60,4
  - The Crisis, 1953 May; MS251.001.002.00110 (Box 2, Folder 110)
    60,5
  - The Crisis, 1953 June-July; MS251.001.002.00111 (Box 2, Folder 111)
    60,6
  - The Crisis, 1953 August-September; MS251.001.002.00112 (Box 2, Folder 112)
    60,7
  - The Crisis, 1953 October; MS251.001.002.00113 (Box 2, Folder 113)
    60,8
  - The Crisis, 1953 November; MS251.001.002.00114 (Box 2, Folder 114)
    60,9
  - The Crisis, 1953 December; MS251.001.002.00115 (Box 2, Folder 115)
    60,10
  - The Crisis, 1954 January; MS251.001.002.00116 (Box 2, Folder 116)
    61,1
  - The Crisis, 1954 February; MS251.001.002.00117 (Box 2, Folder 117)
    61,2
  - The Crisis, 1954 March; MS251.001.002.00118 (Box 2, Folder 118)
    61,3
  - The Crisis, 1954 April; MS251.001.002.00119 (Box 2, Folder 119)
    61,4
  - The Crisis, 1954 May; MS251.001.002.00120 (Box 2, Folder 120)
    61,5
  - The Crisis, 1954 June-July; MS251.001.002.00121 (Box 2, Folder 121)
    61,6
  - The Crisis, 1954 August-September; MS251.001.002.00122 (Box 2, Folder 122)
    61,7
  - The Crisis, 1954 October; MS251.001.002.00123 (Box 2, Folder 123)
    61,8
  - The Crisis, 1954 November; MS251.001.002.00124 (Box 2, Folder 124)
    61,9
  - The Crisis, 1954 December; MS251.001.002.00125 (Box 2, Folder 125)
    61,10
  - The Crisis, 1955 January; MS251.001.002.00126 (Box 2, Folder 126)
    62,1
  - The Crisis, 1955 March; MS251.001.002.00127 (Box 2, Folder 127)
    62,3
  - The Crisis, 1955 April; MS251.001.002.00128 (Box 2, Folder 128)
    62,4
  - The Crisis, 1955 May; MS251.001.002.00129 (Box 2, Folder 129)
    62,5
  - The Crisis, 1955 June-July; MS251.001.002.00130 (Box 2, Folder 130)
    62,6
  - The Crisis, 1955 August-September; MS251.001.003.00001 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    62,7
  - The Crisis, 1955 October; MS251.001.003.00002 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    62,8
  - The Crisis, 1955 November; MS251.001.003.00003 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    62,9
  - The Crisis, 1955 December; MS251.001.003.00004 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    62,10
  - The Crisis, 1956 June-July; MS251.001.003.00005 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    63,6
  - The Crisis, 1957 March; MS251.001.003.00006 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    64,3
  - The Crisis, 1957 April; MS251.001.003.00007 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    64,4
  - The Crisis, 1958 March; MS251.001.003.00008 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    65,3
  - The Crisis, 1958 May; MS251.001.003.00009 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    65,5
  - The Crisis, 1958 June-July; MS251.001.003.00010 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    65,6
  - The Crisis, 1958 November; MS251.001.003.00011 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    65,9
  - The Crisis, 1959 January; MS251.001.003.00012 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    66,1
  - The Crisis, 1959 February; MS251.001.003.00013 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    66,2
  - The Crisis, 1959 March; MS251.001.003.00014 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    66,3
  - The Crisis, 1959 April; MS251.001.003.00015 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    66,4
  - The Crisis, 1959 May; MS251.001.003.00016 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    66,5
  - The Crisis, 1959 June-July; MS251.001.003.00017 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    66,6
  - The Crisis, 1959 August-September; MS251.001.003.00018 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    66,7
  - The Crisis, 1959 November; MS251.001.003.00019 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    66,9
  - The Crisis, 1959 December; MS251.001.003.00020 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    66,10
  - The Crisis, 1960 January; MS251.001.003.00021 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    67,1
  - The Crisis, 1960 February; MS251.001.003.00022 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    67,2
  - The Crisis, 1960 March; MS251.001.003.00023 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    67,3
  - The Crisis, 1960 June-July; MS251.001.003.00024 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    67,6
  - The Crisis, 1960 August-September; MS251.001.003.00025 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    67,7
  - The Crisis, 1960 October; MS251.001.003.00026 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    67,8
  - The Crisis, 1960 November; MS251.001.003.00027 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    67,9
  - The Crisis, 1960 December; MS251.001.003.00028 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    67,10
  - The Crisis, 1961 January; MS251.001.003.00029 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    68,1